the tiny human brains we grow from stem
cells are so much more important than
what we can make robotics with in fact
making human animal chimeras with
organoids is going to change the face of
medicine forever these things are not
without ethical concerns researchers
worldwide are demanding that we start
thinking about the ethics around them
and what is the appropriate way to use
them in science we'll talk about it one
of the big problems in research
particularly medical research is that
it's almost always done in before we go
to human trials while mice are mammals
and they make a great model organism
they're very different than humans one
of the solutions is to incorporate human
parts in them one of the other
applications of chimeric organisms is
breeding mice that already have human
cells it's essentially a disembodied
brain piece and don't get me wrong
there's been a lot of really cool new
research and things that we're
discovering about human diseases that we
wouldn't have been able to find if we
just used mice but we also can't
experiment on a person what chimeras
allow us to do is look at human systems
in something that is not a person
something that's easy to raise and grow
one of the other really cool
applications of making Chimera the
closest thing that we have to a human
that we can experiment on to test
medications and treatments are monkeys
chimeric lines also let us do something
else the lines of stem cells that we
currently have are limited and we all
know that medication behaves differently
and different people using chimeric
organoids allows us to test a wider SWAT
of the population in a single organ one
of the other really cool applications of
making chimeric animals is we can breed
mice that already have human cells
pre-loaded you could even have a
chimeric mouse made with your DNA you
yourself could have a little chimeric
mouse made with your tissue that you
could test cancer treatments on to see
if it would actually work for your body
if you are concerned that no one is
considering the ethics around them
that's simply not true we will see laws
made in the very near future governing
their use